《訴訟雙雄》前情提要
為什么我被停職了  我沒有泄露任何文件
Why am I being suspended? I didn't leak any documents.
你受罰不公
You were unfairly punished,
而我想正式歡迎你回到公司
and I would like to officially welcome you back.
-我要加薪  -行
- I want a raise. - Fine.
如果我決定上法學院
And Pearson Hardman pays for law school
皮爾遜·哈德曼會報銷學費
when I decide to go.
同意
Agreed.
我替你付了買入股份款
I fronted your buy-in.
你怎么能這么做
How could you do that?
你都打算去別的地方工作了
You were about to take a job somewhere else.
我們應該開始對彼此坦誠
We need to start being honest with each other.
你把我撤下來
You want me off this case,
是為了讓我遠離聚光燈
so I don't get anywhere near the spotlight.
從你的角度出發
In your position,
聚光燈可以很快的
the spotlight can become an interrogation lamp
變成審訊燈
pretty damn fast.
以后都會這樣了  對嗎
This is always how it's gonna be, isn't it?
我以為你知道
I thought you knew that.
我知道
I guess I did.
我想讓你利用你的力量
I need you to use your power
從斯科特那里幫我把案子搶過來
to give me this case over Scottie.
你是作為朋友求我  還是讓我還人情
Are you asking as a friend, or are you calling in a chit?
還人情
Calling in a chit.
這和他之前幫你的那個忙有關系嗎
Does this have something to do with that favor he did you?
-是的  -那告訴我是什么事
- Yes. - Tell me what it is.
不行
I can't.
看來我們終究沒有
Guess we're not sharing everything
分享所有秘密了
with each other after all.
該起床了  親愛的
Time to wake up, sweetie.
再讓我睡五分鐘  媽
Oh, five more minutes, Mom.
你剛剛是叫我"媽"了嗎
Did you just call me Mom?
什么  才沒有
What? No.
路易  我以前就說過
Louis, I've said it before.
臥室不許說媽媽
The bedroom is a no-mom-talk zone.
明白
Understood.
你還要趕地鐵呢
You have to catch your train.
那就坐下一班
I'll take the later one.
你誰啊
Who are you,
把我的男朋友路易·利特怎么了
and what have you done with my boyfriend, Louis Litt?
你是說那個
Oh, you mean the guy
在結案陳詞前會汗如泉涌的家伙嗎
who sweats profusely before closing arguments?
對  那家伙不見了
Yeah. Yeah, that guy's gone.
真的嗎
Really?
天哪
Oh, my God.
你身上一滴汗都沒有
You're completely dry.
都是因為你的愛  希拉
Your love has made me dry, Sheila.
我已經改頭換面了
I'm a changed man.
事實上  我要再讓你爽上一個小時
In fact... I'm gonna rock your world for one more hour,
然后出庭殺他們個片甲不留
and then I'm gonna kick some ass in court.
因為今天一切都會很順利
'cause today nothing can go wrong.
今天哥說了算
Today is my goddamn day.
太對了
Yeah. It is.
能把糖給我嗎
Can you pass the sugar?
好
Yeah, of course.
那牛奶呢
Okay, how 'bout that milk?
很好啊
Sounds great.
現在我們都同居了  我跟另一個女人約會
How would you feel about me dating other women
你有什么感覺
now that we're living together and all?
匹薩很好啊
Pizza's perfect.
瑞秋
Rachel.
你怎么了
What's going on?
我收到了學費付款時間表
I got my tuition payment schedule, and...
這么大一筆錢
That is a big bill.
是啊  但問題不在這兒
Yeah, and that's not even the problem.
還記得路易炒了我
Remember when Louis fired me
因為他以為我泄露了文件嗎
because he thought that I was leaking information?
我從沒跟你說過
I never told you about
作為補償我們談好的條件
negotiating the terms of my return.
你說過
Yeah, you did.
-他給你加薪10%  -不止這樣
- He gave you a 10% raise. - That's not all he gave me.
他同意  我去上法學院
He agreed that the firm would pay for me
律所會報銷學費
to go to law school when I got in.
那還有什么問題
So what's the problem?
這談話太尷尬了
It's gonna be an awkward conversation.
瑞秋  你要做律師
Rachel, you want to be a lawyer,
以后會有很多尷尬的談話
you're gonna have to have a lot of awkward conversations.
是  但不是這種
Yeah, but not like this.
我跑去說  "路易  還記得我要求
I mean, "Hey, Louis, do you remember when I demanded
你報銷我的法學院學費嗎"
"that you pay for me to go to law school?
"我知道我能被錄取  你出了不少力
"I get that since then you've now tried to help me get in
而且我們現在是朋友
"and that we're friends,
但你現在真得把錢給我"
but I would really like my money now."
好吧  那就別跟他說
Okay. So don't talk to him.
準備好寫一張二十萬的支票
Just get ready to write a check for $200,000,
因為這將是你未來三年的學費
because that's what it's gonna cost for the next three years.
-那就尷尬談話吧  -祝你好運
- Awkward conversation it is. - Best of luck.
諾瑪  我是路易
Norma, it's Louis.
路易·利特  你上司
Louis Litt, your boss.
現在別跟我耍把戲  女人
Don't play your games with me now, woman.
我半小時后要去做結案陳詞
I'm due for closing arguments in 30 minutes,
我要你幫我拖延一下
and I need you to stall.
不  不要去拉火警  行嗎
No, you do not pull the fire alarm as a tactic, okay?
我要你在不犯罪的情況下
I need you to just buy me ten minutes
幫我拖延十分鐘
without committing a crime.
出租車
Taxi!
來吧  寶貝  乖孩子
There we go. Come on, baby. My man.
不不不  別想搶我的車
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, don't you upstream me.
這是我的出租車  是我的
That's my cab. That's my taxi.
這是我的出租車
This is my cab. This is my cab.
我要起訴你  我要起訴你這么賤
Hey, I'm gonna sue you. I'm gonna sue you for sucking.
我要起訴你沒有...
I'm gonna sue you for not being--
我要你的姓名和出生年月  我要...
Okay, I need your name, date of birth, and I need--
好了  "給利"點吧
All right, let's Litt this up.
你對斯科特做了什么
What did you do to Scottie?
-沒什么  -這可不是沒什么
- Nothing. - That is not nothing.
這可是一杯豆奶焦糖拿鐵
That is a soy caramel latte
另加雙份害怕和內疚
with a double shot of fear and guilt.
這是一杯道歉咖啡
That is an apology coffee.
為什么就不是"最佳男友"咖啡
Why can't it just be an "I'm a great boyfriend" coffee?
如果你真這么好
If you're such a great boyfriend,
怎么會不知道你女友正在去芝加哥
why don't you know that your girlfriend is on her way
給韋克斯勒取證的路上
to Chicago for the Wexler deposition?
我再問一遍  你做了什么
So I repeat, what did you do?
我搶走了弗蘭克林·科利爾的案子
I overruled her on Franklin Courier.
我逼她把案子還給了路易
I made her give the case back to Louis.
你插手了
You got in the middle of it?
為什么
Why would you do that?
我現在不想說這件事  唐娜
Look, I don't want to get into it right now, Donna.
好吧
Okay.
不過哈維  如果你真這么對她了
But, Harvey, if you really did do that to her,
咖啡可擺不平
coffee isn't gonna cut it.
正式說一句  我不是這個目的
For the record, this was not my goal.
利特先生
Mr. Litt.
抱歉  法官大人  我遲到了
Sorry, your honor. Sorry I'm late.
你準備好結案陳詞了嗎
Are you ready for closing arguments?
是的
Yes, I am.
陪審團的女士們先生們
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
控方律師指控了我的委托人很多事
opposing counsel has accused my client of a great many things.
但問題在于
But you see, here's the problem.
他們的指控根本沒有事實根據
They don't have one single fact to back up their claim.
完全沒有
I mean, not one.
你們知道我要做什么嗎  我要挑戰你們
So you know what I'm gonna do? I'm gonna challenge you.
不  別說挑戰了
Actually, no, scratch that.
你們敢不敢找出
I'm gonna dare you to find dispute
我方呈堂證據的漏洞吧
with the facts of this case as we presented them.
你是好人嗎
'cause are you a good person?
是的
Yes.
你是好人嗎  是的
Are you a good person? Yes.
你是  你還記筆記  說明你重視這案子
Are you--actually, you took notes, so I can see you care.
這  就是一個模范陪審團
You see, this is the kind of jury that they teach about.
這樣的陪審團  會聽進去
This is the kind of jury that's gonna hear me
我要說的這三個字
when I say these four words.
你們知道是哪三個字嗎
Do you know what those four words are?
我要你們記住這三個字
Because I want you to remember these four words
一直記到死
to your dying breath.
他  沒  做
He didn't do it!
他沒做
He didn't do it.
利特先生  你沒事吧
Mr. Litt, are you okay?
沒事的  我沒事
I'm all right. Yeah, I'm fine.
法警  叫救護車
Bailiff, call an ambulance.
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
翻譯：愛卿遛小鳥   草草   Reginamoon   珞珞
翻譯：七個柚子醬   油炸電風扇   貓咪賜我速死
校對：油炸電風扇   月月     時間軸：憑陵新月   小式   雯雯記
后期：冰冰愛尖尖     總監：swears
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
訴 訟 雙 雄
第三季   第十四集
就這些了吧  完事了吧
Was that it, are we done?
哈維  你才簽了三張支票
Harvey, you've signed three checks.
怎么了
And?
走吧
Just go.
對了  邁克·羅斯怎么樣了
Oh, by the way, how's Mike Ross doing?
什么意思
What are you talking about?
他剛剛整了斯坦普爾啊
He just came up with the huge Stemple solution.
他好著呢
He's doing great.
看來他沒把我們的對話告訴你了
So I guess he didn't tell you about our little conversation?
什么對話
What conversation?
讓他意識到他的天隨時都可能塌下來的對話
The one where he ran into the fact that he has a glass ceiling.
邁克知道這一點
Mike knows he has a glass ceiling.
現在知道了  之前沒有
He knows, but he didn't know.
我們跟威廉·貝克有點問題
We have a problem with William Beck.
那是誰
Who's William Beck?
海岸容光防曬霜的部門主任
Division head of Coastal Radiance Sunscreen.
他想毀約
He's trying to break his contract.
他簽了競爭沖突條款吧
I assume he has a non-compete.
不  哈維  我蠢到讓他隨心所欲
No, Harvey, I was dumb enough to let him do whatever he wants.
他為什么要離開
Why is he trying to leave?
他有些關于生產線的想法
He has some ideas about the product line
我們不肯實施
that we're not implementing.
他收到其他工作邀請了嗎
Does he have another offer?
-露得清想請他  -不能讓他們得逞
- Neutrogena wants him. - They can't have him.
他可以去星巴克打工  但別想涉足這個市場
He can go work at Starbucks, but he's not touching this market.
抱歉  但或許有其他解決方案
Excuse me, but maybe there's a solution.
海岸容光這一分別專門做保濕護膚品
Coastal Radiance is a division of pure moisture skincare.
把他們改成子公司
Spin them off.
貝克能經營自己的公司
Beck gets to run his own company,
兩家公司的股票都能上漲  對大家都有利
both stocks go up, everybody wins.
如果我想要初級律師來想辦法
If I had wanted the junior associate to come up with an idea,
我就會讓初級律師來想辦法了
I'd have asked the junior associate to come up with an idea.
托尼  他說的沒錯
Tony, he's not wrong.
海岸容光的價值被低估了
Coastal Radiance is undervalued,
這正好能解決這問題
and this fixes that.
貝克已經給我們干了十年了
Beck has been with us for ten years.
或許可以估一下改子公司的成本
Maybe it's worth running the numbers on the spin-off.
我不想估價
I don't want to run the numbers.
我要他馬上滾蛋
I want him out now.
讓你的手下準備好解職文件
So have your boy work up the exit paperwork.
喬納森會簽字的
Jonathan will sign off.
你的公司  你說了算
Your company, your call.
要跟我談談剛剛在里面發生的事嗎
You want to talk about what just happened in there?
不太想談
Not particularly.
你的主意不錯  他該聽你的
Look, it was a good idea. He should've listened to it.
我知道這主意不錯
I know it was a good idea.
我不明白的是你為什么不爭取一下
What I don't know is why you didn't push back.
你剛剛在不在里面啊  我爭取了
Were you in there? I did push back.
你真心爭取的時候  能改變別人的想法
When you push back, you change people's minds,
所以你要么是不認同我的看法
which means either you didn't agree with me
要么就是你懶得去改變他的主意
or you don't care enough to change his mind.
我知道什么時候該去勸人改主意
Look, I know when it's time to change someone's mind
什么時候不行
and when it isn't,
如果剛剛會面時我態度再強硬一些
and all pushing harder in that meeting would've done
也只會讓他更堅決
was make him dig in.
有人贊同我們的  喬納森同意我的主意
We had an ally. Jonathan agreed with me.
對  但隨后他還是服從他老板的意思
Yeah, and then he agreed with his boss,
而我們也得聽他老板的
which is what we're gonna do,
因為這世界就是這樣
because it's the way the world works.
-得了  哈維  -邁克
- Come on, Harvey. - Mike.
這人換律師比換內褲還勤
This man goes through lawyers like a hot knife through butter,
我不能害我們被炒
and I wasn't about to get us fired
只為了保護一個我完全不在乎的人
to protect some guy I don't even give a shit about.
你明白了嗎
Now are you on board with that?
我明白了  能說別的了嗎
I'm on board. Can we move on?
-我沒別的可說  -我有
- I have nothing to move on to. - I do.
你給斯科特打電話道歉了嗎
Have you called Scottie and apologized yet?
道什么歉
Apologize for what?
你是道歉警察嗎
What are you, the apology police?
如果你要受調查
If you're the one under investigation,
我一定加入
I'll sign up for that.
杰西卡  如果你又要找我簽支票
Jessica, if you need me to sign any more checks,
-那現在時機正合適  -是路易的事
- now would be a great time. - It's Louis.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
他雖然沒去參加會議
Even though he didn't show up to the meeting,
卻覺得我們排擠他  于是大發脾氣
he's feeling left out and throwing a hissy fit.
他今早在庭上心臟病發
He had a heart attack in court this morning.
天吶
Oh, my God.
他沒事
He's okay.
我打了電話
I made a call,
給他找了西奈山醫學院最好的心臟病專家
he's got the best cardiologists at Mount Sinai,
那邊說他不會有事
and they say he's going to be fine.
我們應該去看他
We should go see him.
他跟諾瑪說他不希望大家去見他
He told Norma he didn't want anybody to come.
就是說他不好意思  但他希望我去的
That means he's embarrassed, but he wants me there.
我不一定什么時候回來
I'll be back when I'm back.
我們要親自接手他的案子
We handle all his cases personally.
掛著路易名字的案子絕不能掉鏈子
Nothing with Louis' name on it falls through the cracks.
不能讓客戶知道發生了什么事
No client finds out this happened.
-沒問題  -沒問題
- Done. - Done.
我會替我們大家送花給他
I'll send him flowers from all of us.
不行
No.
他過敏
He's allergic.
對花過敏
To flowers?
對所有花嗎
All of them?
你怎么知道
How do you even know that?
我們還是初級律師時
I used to send them to his desk every day
我每天給他送花
when we were associates.
我知道
I know.
我混蛋
I'm an asshole.
他不會有事吧
He's gonna be okay, right?
天啊
Oh, my God.
這太糟了
This is awful.
是啊
Yeah, I know.
我一整個早上都在想著
All morning all I've been thinking about is how
我多不想跟他談學費的事
I don't want to talk to him about the tuition, and now--
瑞秋  別這樣
Hey, Rachel, Rachel. Hey, come on.
看著我
Look at me.
他不會有事的
He's gonna be okay.
他會回來  你們有的是時間
He'll be back, and you guys can have a lifetime
一起工作  一起去看芭蕾
of working together, going to the ballet,
討論些真正尷尬的事
having really awkward conversations.
瑞秋  我下面要說的話
Rachel, I'm gonna say the thing
你可能不會想聽
that I know you don't want to hear.
我現在不想管那些
I don't care about that right now.
這不是什么大事
It doesn't have to be a big deal.
我們都在幫助路易
We've all got Louis' back right now,
而且這種事本來就是杰西卡處理
and Jessica handles this stuff anyway.
去跟她談談
Just talk to her.
我絕不允許你犯心臟病
You are never allowed to have a heart attack.
好嗎
Okay?
遵命
Understood.
路易
Louis.
這是天堂嗎
Is this heaven?
我不知道你為什么會這么想
I can understand why you would think that,
但不是的
But no.
我不知道這是怎么發生的
I don't know how this can happen.
我對我的身體這么在意
I...treat my body like a temple.
但是你也有每周末加班啊
And you've also been commuting every weekend,
而且還老讓你手下的律師氣得你血壓升高
and you let the associates raise your blood pressure.
那是因為他們蠢
It's because they're stupid.
行了  路易  放松
Okay, Louis, relax.
醫生說你脫離危險了
The doctors say you're out of danger,
但你不能情緒激動
but you shouldn't get worked up.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
醫生得允許我出院
The doctors need to let me go.
你剛剛才心臟病發了
You had a heart attack.
假如我的供血少斷半秒鐘
If my blood supply had been cut off for a half-second less,
這次就只會被歸類為一次小心臟事件了
it would've been classified as a minor cardiac event.
那假如多斷了半秒鐘呢
And what if it would have lasted half a second more?
沒多斷
It didn't.
我得回去工作
And I need to get to work.
路易  我是認真的  你得緩緩了
Louis, I'm serious. You have to cut back.
你有可能就這樣死了啊
You could have died.
而假如你出了什么事的話
And if anything were to happen to you...
哈維會變得一團糟  明白嗎
Harvey would be a total mess. Okay?
我會緩緩的
I'll cut back.
那就好
Good.
打擾了  你是叫邁克吧  是嗎
Excuse me. It's mike, right?
是的  你還需要什么嗎
Yeah. Did you still need something?
因為我這邊還沒搞定
Because I haven't finished yet.
確實需要  我一直在找路易
I did. I've been trying to find louis.
他之前沒去開會
He wasn't at the meeting.
-路易現在不在這兒  -那他在哪里
- Louis isn't here. - Where is he?
你要找他干什么
What did you need to see him about?
我想談談發生了什么
I want to talk about what happened.
好吧
Yeah, um,
我知道我倆都認為
look, I know that we both agreed
分拆是個更好的辦法  但是
that a spin-off was the better way to go, but--
分拆:從原公司分出一部分  成立獨立的公司
我不想談這個
I don't want to talk about that.
我想談談我自己
I want to talk about me.
我想退出
I want out.
你想離開揚諾普洛斯
You want to leave Gianopolous
就因為今天早上發生的事嗎
because of what happened this morning?
今天早上發生的事情每天都會上演一遍
What happened this morning happens every day.
他會打壓達到了一定位置的人
He keeps people down when they reach a certain point,
而我確定我現在就在那個位置
and I'm pretty sure I'm at that point.
-是的  我明白了  -不  你不明白
- Yeah, I get it. - No, you don't.
你不明白的  你不
You don't. No.
在像這樣的地方
In a place like this,
你的整個未來鋪展在你面前
your whole future's laid out for you.
你四十歲之前就能接管這里
You'll be running the place before 40.
喬納森  我們是為托尼·揚諾普洛斯工作的
Jonathan, we work for Tony Gianopolous.
雖然我知道自己沒必要告訴你
And I know I don't have to tell you,
但你和威廉·貝克是受同一個
but you're working under the same non-compete
非競爭條款約束的
that William Beck is.
但你們也是為我工作的
But you work for me too.
路易是我的私人律師
Louis is my personal attorney.
我知道
I know.
但假如出現了利益沖突
But if there's a conflict of interest,
我們是會站在他那邊的
we're gonna choose him.
我知道你們有沖突
I know that you have a conflict.
我就問問  有沒有什么辦法你們能幫我
I'm just asking, is there any way that you can help me
而且
without...
不是刻意幫助我
helping me?
抱歉了
I'm sorry.
那路易在哪里
Then where's Louis?
路易現在出差去了
Louis is away on business right now,
所以他也幫不了你
so he can't help you either.
那我就找個能幫我的人
Then I'll find someone who will.
這把這當成是我炒掉他的正式通知吧
Let this serve as formal notice I'm letting him go.
密西根州上訴法院
Michigan court of appeals.
什么
What?
幾年前那里有個判決
There was a ruling a few years ago
承認了非競爭條款中的一個薄弱環節
that established a weak link in the non-compete.
抱歉打擾了  您有時間嗎
I'm sorry to interrupt. Do you have a minute?
我能為你做點什么
What can I do for you?
現在真不是提這個的好時機
The timing on this is terrible,
我為此道歉
and I-I apologize for that.
是什么事
What is it?
我需要付法學院學費的第一張支票
I need the first check for my law school tuition.
你說什么
Excuse me?
可能您不記得了  但當我被錯誤的解雇時
Maybe you don't remember, but when I was wrongfully dismissed,
回聘我的條件之一
one of the terms of my rehiring
就是律所幫我支付法學院的學費
was that the firm pays for my law school.
我記得可清楚了
I remember just fine.
而且我記得回聘你的唯一條件
And the only term of your rehiring
就是把你的工資上調10%
was a 10% increase in salary.
什么
What?
不  我告訴您  這是商定好了的條件
No, I'm--I'm telling you this was an agreed-upon term,
-而且  - 而且我告訴你
- and-- - and I'm telling you
我對此毫不知情
I know nothing about that.
還有就算我知道這件事
And if I had heard about it,
我也絕對不會同意的
I would have never approved it.
我給這家律所當了替罪羊
I was scapegoated by this firm.
所以當你同意回來時
And when you agreed to come back,
我們給你加了10%的工資
you were given a 10% raise.
那是標準
That's standard.
我這可不是標準情況
My situation was not standard.
在哪方面不是
In what way?
路易指控我對公司不忠
Louis accused me of being disloyal.
然后呢
And?
然后最后發現他錯了
And he turned out to be wrong.
瑞秋  問題是
The problem, Rachel,
你口說無憑
is that you have no record of what you're saying.
他同意了的
He agreed to it.
他是您手下的人
He is your agent.
您和他是綁在一塊的
You're bound by this.
我不知道這件事
I don't know that.
而且那人剛剛心臟病發了
And the man just had a heart attack.
所以我也不會打電話問他這件事
And I'm not going to call him and ask him.
我知道  我也不希望你打
I know that, and I don't want you to.
那這個談話就結束了
Then this conversation is over.
艾弗森醫生  請到心臟實驗室
Dr. Iverson to the cardiac lab.
-你這到底是在干什么  -希拉
- What the hell are you doing?  - Sheila.
-我很抱歉  -你確實應該
- I'm so sorry.  - You should be.
我不知道我怎么會有心臟病
I don't know why I had a heart attack,
但我保證這不會再發生了
but I promise it won't happen again.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
你以為我是因為你心臟病發而生氣嗎
You think I'm mad because you had a heart attack?
這是軟弱的表現  你恨軟弱
It's a sign of weakness. You hate weakness.
不  我恨的是你居然還在工作
No, I hate that you're doing work.
-希拉...  -不  路易
- Sheila-- - No, Louis,
你知道我來這里的一路上在想什么嗎
do you know what I was thinking about the whole way down here?
我在想假如你死了
I was thinking that if you died,
我也不想活了
I'd want to die too.
所以你最好開始好好照顧自己
So you better start taking care of yourself,
因為我不想...
because I don't want to--
-希拉...  -不  不許再工作了
- Sheila-- - No. No more work.
好的  但這不是你想象的那樣
Okay, but this isn't what you think it is.
別和我爭這個  拜托了
Don't fight me on this, please.
好吧  但是我需要那個
Okay, but I need that--
別和我爭這個
Don't fight me on this!
"希拉  自從我認識你以來
"Sheila, as long as I've known you,
我一直有...
I've had a...
我一直有一種完滿的感覺
I've had a feeling of completeness.
羅密歐與朱麗葉
Romeo and Juliet.
安東尼與克莉奧佩特拉[埃及艷后]"
Antony and Cleopatra."
你把詹姆和瑟曦·蘭尼斯特劃掉了
You crossed out Jaime and Cersei Lannister.
《冰與火之歌》角色
我覺得這對太有爭議性了[親兄妹]
I thought they were too controversial a couple.
對什么而言太有爭議性了
Too controversial for what?
對求婚而言
A proposal.
什么
What?
希拉  我本可能死掉的
Sheila, I could've died.
而我不希望我的人生終結了卻沒能...
And I don't want my life to have ended without--
路易  我不希望你問出你將要問我的問題
Louis, I don't want you to ask me what you're about to ask me
只是因為你不想孤老終生
because you're afraid to die alone.
不是的
No.
這個和那個無關
It's not about that.
這和孤老終生無關
It's not about dying alone.
這事關過一種沒有我愛的女人的生活
It's about living without the woman I love.
希拉·阿曼達·塞茲
Sheila Amanda Sazs,
你是我此生摯愛  希望此生永久
You are the love of what I hope will be my very, very long life.
沒有你的日子  我一秒都過不下去
And I can't spend one more second of it without you.
你愿意嫁給我嗎
Will you marry me?
我愿意
Yes.
我愿意嫁給你
Yes, I'll marry you.
托尼  有什么能幫你的嗎
Tony, what can I do for you?
你耍了我
You screwed me over.
就因為我想辦法炒了你讓我們炒的人
By figuring out how to fire the guy you told us to fire?
因為你教我的副手如何違背非競爭條款
By telling my Number Two how to break his non-compete.
-我沒干過這種事  -那就是路易·利特
- I did nothing of the kind. - Then it was Louis Litt.
不可能  根本沒這種事
No way. That did not happen.
少扯淡  哈維  我們開過會了
That's bullshit, Harvey, we had a meeting.
喬納森本來文書工作做得好好的
Jonathan stuck around for the paperwork.
突然他帶著辭職信來了
Then suddenly he comes back with his resignation
還有密歇根上訴法院關于破壞這種協議的
and some Michigan appeals court precedent
判決先例
for breaking our deal.
他肯定沒見過路易
Well, he couldn't have met with Louis
路易都不在辦公室
because Louis wasn't even in the office.
那就是別人
Then it was someone else.
托尼  你到底想怎么樣
Tony, what exactly do you want?
你想讓我像炒了貝克一樣炒了他嗎
You want me to fire him like we're firing Beck?
告訴你一個小秘密
I'll tell you a little secret.
我壓根不在乎貝克走不走
I don't give a shit whether Beck goes or not.
不過你知道我為什么想整垮他嗎
But can you understand why I want him crushed?
因為你想讓喬納森·西德威爾那樣的人
Because you want people like Jonathan Sidwell
知道試圖離開的后果
to know what happens when they try to leave.
我的律師總算是開竅了
Finally my lawyer shows up.
我一直都心中有數
Oh, I've been here the whole time.
隨你怎么說
You see it how you want to see it.
不過如果你不能想辦法留住喬納森
But if you can't figure out a way to make Jonathan stay,
要走的就是你
you'll be the one who's gone.
托尼
Tony.
這事我會處理  不過話要說清楚
I'm gonna fix this, but let's get one thing clear.
我和之前那些被你炒掉律師不一樣
I'm not like the other lawyers you've burned through.
如果下次你再像個四歲小孩一樣
So the next time you go stomping around
氣得跳腳  沖我亂發脾氣
like a four-year-old throwing tantrums with me,
我會先炒了你
I'll be the one getting rid of you.
看來你還是沒跟我一起行動
Guess you were never really on board after all.
什么  我起草了關于貝克的文件了
What? I did the paperwork for Beck.
我說的不是貝克
I'm not talking about Beck.
我說的是喬納森·西德威爾
I'm talking about Jonathan Sidwell.
密歇根上訴法庭聽著耳熟嗎
Michigan court of appeals sound familiar?
哈維  他打算炒了路易
Harvey, he was gonna fire Louis.
如果他向路易征求的是這種建議
If that's the advice he was looking for from Louis,
那他總會炒了他的
he'd have fired him anyway.
那喬納森也總會找到那個漏洞的
And Jonathan would've found that loophole anyway.
可他沒自己找  而是由你告訴了他
But instead he got it from you.
你想讓我怎么做  路易犯了心臟病
What do you want from me? Louis had a heart attack.
-杰西卡讓我們別...  -別找借口了
- Jessica told us not to--  - Don't hide behind that shit.
說重點吧
Let's get into what this is really about.
你在說什么
What the hell are you talking about?
我在說你和杰西卡的對話
I'm talking about your conversation with Jessica.
所以你才在我們見過揚諾普洛斯后
So that's why you were telling me my idea was so good
說我的主意很棒
after our Gianopolous meeting.
沒錯  我們談過了
Yeah. We had that conversation.
而且沒錯  談得糟透了
And yeah, it sucks.
但那與此無關
But this has nothing to do with that.
-那就證明  -證明什么
- Then prove it.  - Prove what?
他對自己的現狀很不滿
He's unhappy with his situation.
人對現狀不滿時  就會去找出路
When people are unhappy, they find a way out.
這就證明了我的觀點
Which brings me back to my point.
你確實沒跟我一起行動
You weren't really on board.
我說了  我處理好貝克了
I told you, I took care of Beck.
現在你也得處理好喬納森了
Well, now you're gonna do the same for Jonathan.
密歇根的法庭判決明確指出他...
The Michigan ruling clearly states that he has--
別給我引用法庭判決
Don't quote precedent to me.
是你找出了違反非競爭條款的方法
You figured out how he could break the non-compete,
那你就再去找出強制執行的方法
now figure out how to enforce it.
-哈維  -夠了
- Harvey--  - Enough.
只要你想  你會是個很出色的律師
You're a pretty good lawyer when you want to be,
所以這次不如試著站在我們這邊吧
so maybe try doing it for our side this time.
晚上過得很糟嗎
Bad night?
如果絞盡腦汁
Only if you call figuring out a way
毀人夢想算糟的話  那今晚是挺糟
to crush someone's hopes and dreams bad.
你呢
What about you?
那個尷尬的對話怎么樣了
You, uh, take care of that awkward conversation?
那不是尷尬  那是...
Yeah, it wasn't awkward. It was...
羞辱
humiliating.
路易根本沒跟杰西卡說過
Louis never actually told Jessica.
什么  太扯了
What? That's bullshit.
他承諾過我的  而他是公司的代表
He made a promise to you. He's an agent of the firm.
我從來沒想過會這樣
You know, I never thought about that.
或許我該直接沖到他病床前
Maybe I should just rush to his hospital bed
逼他承認他耍了我
and get him to admit that he screwed me over.
他怎么能這么騙我
How could he lie to me like that?
瑞秋  他為什么騙你這不重要
Rachel, why he lied to you doesn't matter.
-對我來說很重要  -你自己說的
- It matters to me.  - Well, you said it yourself.
你真想讓他難過嗎  就為了找出原因
Do you really want to upset him just to find out?
當然不
Of course not.
那就去掉情緒的因素
Then take the emotion out of it.
-你在說什么  -這是合同上的問題
- What are you talking about? - It's a contract problem.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
想出辦法來強制執行合同
Figure out a way to enforce the contract.
有人想見你
I have someone here to see you.
唐娜  我現在沒時間見任何人
Donna, I don't have time to see anyone right--
看看誰來了  你之前都去哪兒了
Oh, look who it is. Where the hell have you been?
哈維  別那么刻薄  他剛犯過心臟病
Harvey, don't be a dick. He had a heart attack.
你以為犯個心臟病
And you think having a heart attack
就有權休假了
gives you the right to take the day off?
我還活著
I'm alive.
救命
Help me.
回抱他
Hug him back.
你倆單獨待會吧
I'm gonna let you two be alone.
我不是不喜歡這樣  不過...
Okay, not that I'm not enjoying this, but...
你不該在家待著嗎
shouldn't you be home?
不  醫生說我可以回來了
No, the doctor cleared me to come back.
希拉允許我每天工作半天
Sheila's allowing me half days.
剩下的半天
The other half of the day...
我就在家籌備婚禮
I'm at home planning my wedding.
你們訂婚了
You're engaged?
那是我人生中最美好的一刻
It's the happiest moment of my life.
我對準新娘深表同情
I'll send my condolences to the bride-to-be.
這種幽默感
That kind of sense of humor
正是我想要的伴郎所需要的
is exactly what I want of my best man.
路易  你是在請我當你的伴...
Louis, are you asking me to be your best--
哈維  在回答之前
Harvey, before you answer,
我很抱歉讓你在我和斯科特之間進退兩難
I am sorry my fight with Scottie put you in a bad situation.
我知道讓你還我人情
And I know calling in my chit with you
傷害了我們間的友誼  但...
jeopardized our friendship, but...
-路易  -聽我說完
- Louis--  - Let me just finish.
你說我不能二者兼得  但...
You said I can't have it both ways, but--
我很榮幸
I'd be honored.
謝謝你  哈維
Thank you, Harvey.
不客氣  路易
You're welcome, Louis.
-科瓦克先生  -什么事
- Mr. Kovacs. - Yes?
我是邁克·羅斯  皮爾遜-斯佩克特律所
Mike Ross. Pearson Specter.
我們有生意往來嗎
Do we have business together?
喬納森·西德威爾
Jonathan Sidwell.
我知道你給了他一份工作
I understand you made him an offer
管理你的投資部
to run your investment division.
喬納森給我看了一份提案  很合我意
Jonathan reached out to me with a proposal, and I liked it.
那他有沒有說起過
Did he happen to mention the fact
他簽了非競爭條款呢
that he's under a non-compete?
說了
Yes.
他也說了
He also mentioned that
根據密歇根上訴法庭的審判結果
the Michigan court of appeals decision
他可以違反那個條款
makes his contract breakable.
我讓律師查了  他說得沒錯
I had my lawyers look into it. He's right.
你讓你的律師
Did you also have your lawyers
調查侵犯知識產權了嗎
look into the theft of intellectual property?
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
我說的是喬納森發明的
I'm talking about the algorithm
鑒定一個公司
that Jonathan developed to identify
是否達到收購標準的算法
companies ripe for takeover.
-我的雇員  我的算法  -錯
- My employee, my algorithm.  - Wrong.
喬納森發明這個算法的時候
Jonathan developed it while under contract
還受雇于托尼·揚諾普洛斯  因此這個算法屬于后者
with Tony Gianopolous, which makes it his property.
-你想要什么  -什么都不要
- What do you want?  - I don't want anything.
我來這里
I just came down here
只是為了告訴你
to let you know you can go ahead
你和 喬納森·西德威爾怎么樣我不管
and do whatever you care to with Jonathan Sidwell,
但如果你用了他的算法
but if you use his algorithm,
我們會通過法律追討你因此所得的每分錢
we're gonna sue you for every penny that comes from it.
聽說你回來了
I heard you were back.
-你該這么動嗎  -處方寫的
- Should you be doing that?  - Prescribed.
慢走  得讓血液循環起來
Light walking. Need to get the blood flowing.
好
Okay.
很好
Good.
路易
Look, louis, I am--
你的事情我很遺憾  真心的
I'm sorry about what happened. I really am.
我會好起來的  瑞秋
Well, I'm gonna be fine, Rachel.
好
Good.
實際上我想和你討論一個合同問題
I actually wanted to talk to you about a contracts issue.
-開始  -好
- Shoot.  - Okay.
我的一個朋友  和一個公司代表
A friend of mine entered into a verbal agreement
達成了一個口頭契約  現在對方食言了
with an agent for a corporation, and now he's reneging on it.
等等  為什么口頭契約
Wait a second, why verbal?
為什么不
Why not?
口頭契約也收法律保護的  她知道
Verbal contracts are binding, and she knows it.
-錄音了嗎  -沒有
- She have it on tape?  - No.
那對方可以說謊  或者爭論字面問題
Well, then he can lie about it, or he can argue the wording.
不  對方做出了明確保證
No, he made a clear promise.
或許是不確定的承諾  承諾去試試
Well, maybe it was a promise to try,
-或許是個建議  -不是的
- or maybe it was a suggestion.  - No, it wasn't.
什么契約
What's the contract?
雇傭獎金
Employment bonus.
一次性支付  還是按期支付
Lump sum or payable over time?
-三年期限  -那口頭就屁用沒有了
- Three-year term.  - Well, then verbal ain't shit.
如果期限超過一年  就必須落筆
If it's paid over a year or more, it has to be written.
我朋友根據這個承諾  做了重大的決定
My friend made life decisions based on this promise.
她可以告對方  允諾禁反言
She could sue for promissory estoppel.
如果允諾者做出允諾  被允諾者因此而行事
若允諾者食言  則需賠付相應損失
她可以告做出承諾的那個混蛋
Well, she could sue the dick who made the deal,
但沒法告公司
but she can't sue the company.
-她不想那么做  -我問問你
- She doesn't want to do that.  - Let me ask you this.
如果合法的話  為什么不落筆寫好
Why wouldn't she get it in writing if it was legit?
因為她信任他
Because she trusted him.
她不知道為什么會被他欺騙
She doesn't know why he would lie to her.
他欺騙  因為他可以
He did because he could.
他想在那時那刻達成這個目的
He wanted what he wanted when he wanted it,
對他毫無損失
and it cost him nothing.
-明白嗎  -明白
- You know?  - Yeah.
-或許她應該去告他  -她可以試試
- Maybe she should go after him.  - She could try.
但從實際出發  她會輸  應該輸
But I mean, realistically, she'll lose, and she should,
因為愚蠢不應該被獎勵
because stupidity shouldn't be rewarded.
你來找我真是太好了  讓我回復了活力
So glad you came to see me. You really got my juices going.
讓我覺得回到這里很高興
Make me feel glad to be back.
-這太好了 未婚夫  -非常好  未婚妻
- This is nice, fiance.  - It is nice, betrothed.
我們應該在哪兒開始呢
So where should we do it?
希拉  真的嗎  我剛經歷了心臟病發作
Sheila, are you serious? I just had a heart attack.
我說的是婚禮
I'm talking about the wedding.
我希望就在這兒舉行
I say we do it here.
在紐約結婚
Get married in New York?
這是我們開始的地方
It's where our relationship began.
我覺得在這里定終身最合適
I think it's only fitting that we tie the knot here.
我愛你
I love you.
好  那就定了
Good, then it's decided.
我們在這結婚
We'll do it here
然后直接搬去波士頓
and then move straight to Boston.
什么叫搬去波士頓啊
What do you mean move to Boston?
我不會搬的
I'm not moving to Boston.
你必須搬  你知道哈佛對我意味著什么
You have to. You know what Harvard means to me.
你也知道這家律所對我多重要
You know what Pearson Specter means to me.
路易  那里有很多律所
Okay, Louis, there are a dozen firms
會毫不猶豫地搶你
that would snap you up in a second there.
這里的法學院也是
Same goes for law schools here.
是  但都不是哈佛
Yeah, but they're not Harvard,
也就是說都是第二等的
which means they're second tier.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
你真的以為我會放下一切
You seriously expected me to drop everything
搬到紐約來嗎
and move to New York?
是  我是這么想
Yeah, I did.
好吧  我覺得你也太自信了
Okay, well, I think that's a little presumptuous.
我嗎
Me?
那你呢
What about you?
你還建議我們搬去培根山呢
You're the one who has us buying a place on Bacon Hill.
首先  是燈塔山  我以為你喜歡那
Okay, it's "Beacon Hill," and I thought you liked it.
波士頓最好 最昂貴的街區
去旅游是挺好  不是生活
To visit. I mean, not to live.
你怎么能說這里的法學院是二等呢
And what are you talking about, our law schools are second tier?
波士頓才是二等呢
Your city is second tier.
也許我的城市是二等
Well, maybe my city is second tier.
可那是你嘴上說愛著的女人的家
But it's also the home of the woman you supposedly love.
希拉  別這樣
Oh, Sheila, come on, please.
我的一切都在紐約
I mean, everything I have is in New York.
是除了我的一切
Everything except me.
如果你雙眼盯著屏幕
It's usually easier if you look at the screen
會簡單點
with your eyes.
抱歉
I'm--I'm sorry.
這一周很不順
It's just been one of those weeks.
你知道路易會沒事的  對吧
You know Louis is gonna be okay, right?
是  我知道他沒事
Yeah, I know he's going to be okay.
但眼下這時  我恨他
But at the moment, I hate his guts.
我聽說你有喜事
I hear congratulations are in order.
杰西卡
Jessica.
又一個單身漢跳進婚姻的墳墓
Another eligible bachelor bites the dust.
是啊  不是  這事...
Yeah. I mean, no, it's--
很美好
It's amazing.
你感覺怎么樣
How are you feeling?
好多了  謝謝
Better, thanks.
我想給你個祝康復的小禮物
I wanted to get you a little welcome-back something.
不是貴重的東西
It's not much.
你這周真讓我嚇了一跳
You know, you gave me quite a scare this week.
我愛這照片
I love it.
是五年前的律師聚會
The Pearson Hardman retreat five years ago.
你知道那晚讓我記憶最深的是什么嗎
And do you know what I remember most about that night?
你跳舞跳得真好
What an amazing dancer you are.
在長島芭蕾學校學了五年
Five years, Long Island school of ballet.
你那晚可沒跳芭蕾
You weren't dancing ballet that night.
芭蕾是一切舞蹈的基礎
Well, they say ballet is the foundation for everything.
先生  你的基礎很好
Well, sir, you have an amazing foundation.
我就是覺得可以把這張加到你的收藏里
I just thought you could add that to your collection.
不要只有你和布魯諾
Somewhere between you and... Bruno.
你對我很重要
It means so much to me that you...
路易
Louis.
好了
Come on.
我們一起經歷了這么多
After everything we've been through,
你就是家人
you're family.
我的天
Holy shit.
可不是
I know.
他背叛了我
He betrayed me.
也許  可是瑞秋
Maybe, but, Rachel,
你都沒給他一個解釋的機會
you didn't even give him a chance to explain himself.
我不想讓他不安
I didn't want to upset him.
即便他當時騙了你
Even if he was bullshiting you back then,
我認識的路易是說到做到的
the Louis I know is a man of his word.
而如果你能直白地...
And if you went to him honestly--
那沒用的
It wouldn't matter.
他只會說他同意
He would just say he agreed to it,
但杰西卡還是會反對
and Jessica would still say no.
他可能會主動幫你付的
He might offer to pay.
當然不行  我不會允許的
Absolutely not. I wouldn't let him.
而你知道嗎  這不是問題所在
And you know what, that's not the problem.
問題是什么
What is the problem?
問題在于他讓我成了個傻子
The problem is he made me a chump.
瑞秋
Rachel--
唐娜  我以一個
Donna, I went in there
律師助理的身份與路易·利特協商
as a paralegal trying to negotiate with Louis Litt,
拿到了足夠讓我成為律師的錢
and I left with the money to become a lawyer,
這是我人生中第一次覺得
and for the first time in my life,
我真的能成為一名律師
I felt like I could actually be one.
而現在我意識到
And now I realize that...
當我離開的時候
when I left that room,
他大概在笑他是怎么占了我便宜的
he was probably laughing about how he pulled one over on me.
也許你說得沒錯
Maybe you're right.
但我告訴你  今天的路易絕不會這樣做
But I'm telling you, the Louis of today would never do that.
那今天的瑞秋也不可能
Well, the Rachel of today certainly wouldn't
就這么放過他
let him get away with it.
而今天的唐娜是個天才
And the Donna of today is a genius.
不  唐娜哪天不是天才嘛
Well, the genius of Donna is every day.
你想說什么
What are you saying?
你只是不能找路易麻煩
Just because you can't go after Louis
并不代表你不能拿到錢
doesn't mean you can't still make your case.
你是有什么毛病
What the hell is wrong with you?
你給我地圖讓我逃跑
You gave me the map to escape
又告訴守衛我在哪
and told the guards where I'd be.
-喬納森  -科瓦克撤銷了委托
- Jonathan-- - Kovacs rescinded his offer.
他說我沒有那套算法就不值錢了
He said I'm not worth it without that algorithm.
-聽著  我很抱歉  -抱歉
- Listen, I'm sorry. - Sorry?
是你先給我那個建議的
You gave me that advice in the first place.
那是因為你威脅你要炒掉路易
Because you threatened to leave Louis.
胡扯
Bullsh--.
你這樣做是因為你知道我在和誰作對
You did it because you knew what I was up against,
而你想幫我
and you were trying to help me.
不管是為了什么
Whether that's true or not,
那個建議都是私下的
that advice was off the record,
而現實中我的工作是阻止你
and it turns out that on the record it's my job to stop you.
呵呵  恭喜
Well, congratulations.
你剝奪了我最珍視的東西
You ripped away the thing I value the most.
那套算法  我花了十年開發
that algorithm-- it took me ten years to develop it.
那是我評估公司的方法
It's how I look at valuing companies.
是我評價世界的方法
It's how I look at the world.
如果我沒有了它
If I can't take it with me,
即使別人認為我有價值  我還是一文不值
even if someone thinks I'm worth something, I'm not.
-喬納森  -求你了
- Jonathan-- - Please.
臺面上的事你已經做過了
You did your job on the record.
私下里你告訴我  我該怎么辦
Now off the record, what do I do?
我的工作就是確保你無計可施
It was my job to make sure there's nothing you could do.
那這十年里你盡管看著
Then check in with me in ten years.
我只能在不變的職位上
'Cause I promise you I'll be at the same desk
上相同的班
punching the same clock.
不能升職  也不能離開
Can't move up, can't move out.
拜你所賜
It's on you.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
你是對的
You were right.
這不是威廉·貝克和喬納森·西德威爾的問題
This isn't about William Beck or Jonathan Sidwell.
是我的問題
It's about me.
邁克
Mike--
我想讓自己合法化
I want to go legit.
你不能
You can't.
哈維  聽著
Harvey, listen--
我說得不夠清楚嗎
Do I need to state the obvious?
我現在可以去讀法學院  拿到真正的文憑
I can go to law school now, all right? Get a real degree.
即使你之前
Even if it didn't matter
假裝拿到了哈佛法學院文憑的事
that you've already presented yourself
無人追究
as having gone to Harvard Law,
你還要再考一次律師資格考試
you'd have to take the bar again.
我過了一次  第二次也會過的
Okay, I passed it once, I'll pass it again.
第一次不是以你自己的名字考的
Not under your own name.
而且如果你現在去考
And if you take it now,
許多人都會注意到你
you'll draw attention to yourself in a major way.
那我找羅拉·詹森黑進資格考名單
Then I get Lola Jensen to hack into the bar
把我名字加進去  就像她黑哈佛一樣
and just put me in there, just like she did with Harvard.
你瘋了嗎
Are you insane?
黑資格考的話你就是
Hacking into the bar is twice the crime
第二次違法了
you've been committing.
不想被人抓到辮子
Rule number one of not getting caught,
就是別輕舉妄動
you don't move the goddamn body.
但要被人發現的話就不一樣了
You do if they're about to find it.
沒人會發現的
They're not about to find it.
隨時會被發現
They're always about to find it!
邁克  用一個謊話來圓另一個謊話
Mike, committing another fraud to cover your fraud
是不能讓你合法化的
isn't going legit.
這只是掩蓋而已  并不能否認
It's just covering your ass, and it doesn't undo
你犯過法的事實
the fact that you've already committed the crime.
你以為我沒想過這些嗎
You think I haven't thought about all of this?
哈維  我無路可走了
Harvey, I'm stuck.
進也不是  退也不是
There's no way up, there's no way down.
我不能這樣過一輩子
I can't live my whole life like this.
好吧
Okay.
你想合法化
You want to be legit,
只有一個辦法
there's only one way.
你去找個愛荷華的小鎮
You go to a small town in Iowa
那里沒人知道哈維·斯佩克特
where nobody's ever heard of Harvey Specter,
杰西卡·皮爾遜和其他人
Jessica Pearson, or anybody else.
你去讀法學院  開個小公司
You go to law school, hang out your shingle.
沒人會知道
Nobody will ever know.
我保證你會在那小角落稱王
I guarantee you'd be king of the hill.
但你永遠不能回到大地方
But you could never come back to the mountain.
不能回來紐約  芝加哥  或洛杉磯
Not here in New York, Chicago, or L.A.
人多嘴雜  人們總會知道
Someone will know someone,
就前功盡棄了
and it'll all be for nothing.
我不能  你明知道的
I can't do that, and you know it.
我知道
I do know it.
邁克  你現在在律政之都
Mike, you're in the major leagues,
你可以面對面和最好的高手過招
and you get to go toe-to-toe with the best there is.
我不敢說這對你是不是這輩子值了
And I can't tell you if that's enough for a lifetime,
但如果你想留下  你就別無他法
but if you want to stay, there's nothing more you can do.
我的建議就是抓緊時間享受
My advice is hold on tight and enjoy the ride.
你來干嘛
What are you doing here?
我來幫你的
I'm here to help you.
你說過沒辦法阻止你做過的事
You said there was no way to stop what you did.
法律途徑不行  交易可行
This isn't a legal solution. It's a business solution.
一場眾人皆贏的交易
One where everybody wins.
眾人皆贏
Everybody wins?
這是你對貝克說過的話
That's what you said about Beck.
所以你要我也去開自己的公司
So you want me to spin off my own company,
我運營  他控股
I run it, he owns it?
我可沒那么說
I never said that.
好吧  他不和貝克一起合作
Well, he didn't go for it with Beck.
怎么會同意跟我呢
Why would he go for it with me?
因為他根本不屑于威廉·貝克
Because he doesn't give a sh-- about William Beck.
你說什么
What are you saying?
你每天都在開發你的算法
You develop your algorithm every day.
當然了
Of course.
不然的話算法就無效了
It's useless if I don't.
對  但這并不是你這樣做的原因
Right, but that's not why you do it.
你這樣做是因為你熱愛它
You do it because you love it.
好吧  他可以強迫我留下
Well, he can force me to stay,
但他不能逼我愛上它
but he can't force me to love it.
而這就是你的籌碼
And that's exactly where your leverage is.
如果你不熱愛你的工作  就會讓他錢財有損
If you don't love what you do, it costs him a fortune.
而他知道這一點
And he knows it.
那可不一定
This isn't a sure thing.
所以我相信如果不管用
Which is why I'm trusting he won't know
他也不會知道是我的建議
it came from me if it doesn't work.
你為什么要這么做
Why are you doing this?
就當我是熱愛我的工作吧
Let's just say I love my job...
但我知道被困住是什么感覺
But I know what it feels like to be trapped.
唐娜說你想見我
Donna said you wanted to see me
因為一些管理上的破事
about some more managerial bullshit.
什么
What?
你不覺得我已經吸取了支票的教訓了嗎
Don't you think I learned my lesson with the checks?
-那你找我干嘛  -你是來聽我說話的
- Then why am I here? - You're here to listen to me.
你知道這是要做什么嗎
Do you know what this is about?
知道  而且我已經告訴過你
Yes. And I already told you--
我來這不是為了要求你接受路易的合同
I am not here to ask you to honor Louis' contract.
我是來讓你給我一個新合同
I am here to ask you to make a new one with me.
我們跟你的合同
Our contract with you
是在你畢業后為你提供一份工作
is a promise of a job when you get out,
不是給你交學費
Not paying for you on your way in.
我手里的名單上有
I have a list here of the signing bonuses
這里三個律師簽約時許諾的獎金
of the top three associates who have come into this firm.
把我的獎金預支給我
Give me an advance on mine.
上次我們談判的時候  你說
The last time we negotiated, you said,
如果得不到回報就不要簽任何東西
"Never sign something without getting something in return."
你得到的回報就是
What you're getting in return
我繼續在這里兼職工作
is that I keep working here part-time.
預支的獎金加上我的薪水就夠我的學費了
The advance, plus my salary, will cover my tuition.
助理掙不了那么多
Paralegals don't make that much.
那些錢加起來也不夠
Those numbers don't add up.
我不是說我要當助理
I'm not proposing being a paralegal.
初級律師那樣的工作
Some of the associates work as lawyers,
我也可以
and I can do the same.
你想得還真快
You came up with that pretty fast.
就像是你想讓我
It's almost as if you wanted me
問你我能得到什么回報一樣
to ask you what I get in return.
-成交嗎  -有個問題
- Do we have a deal? - One problem.
你已經讓我破例了一次了
You already asked me to break precedent once
我放棄了非哈佛不要的規矩
when I waived the Harvard rule.
我不會再為交學費而破例
I'm not breaking it again to pay for law school.
我沒有讓你打破任何規矩
I'm not asking you to break anything.
你已經有過先例了  就是他
You already established precedence, with him.
在你為他交學費的時候
When you paid for his law school.
知道這事的人可不多
That is not common knowledge.
確實不多
No, it's not.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
所以她才想讓我在這
That's why she wanted me here.
我就是活例子
I'm exhibit a.
你對哈維做了投資
You made an investment in Harvey,
我覺得這投資很成功
and I think that turned out pretty well.
我可以反駁你的觀點
I could argue that point.
不  瑞秋說得對  我確實很棒
No, Rachel's right. I'm pretty awesome.
我猜你已經寫好合同了
I assume you have this in writing.
沒寫好的話我就不值這個合同了
I wouldn't be worth it if I didn't.
讓我猜猜看  他同意了
Let me guess. He went for it.
是的
He did.
你想讓我幫你建立新公司嗎
You want me to set up your new corporation?
我想讓你加入我的新公司
I want you to join my new corporation.
這是一封錄用函
It's an offer letter.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你說你知道被困住是什么感覺
You said you know what it's like to feel trapped.
我覺得你想找個出路
Thought maybe you'd like a way out.
-我還說我熱愛我的工作  -也許吧
- I also said I love what I do. - Maybe.
讓我告訴你我以前跟路易·利特說過什么
But let me tell you what I once told Louis Litt.
我們不是律師  我們是投資銀行家
We're not lawyers. We're investment bankers.
我們的工作比你們的厲害多了
Our job blows yours out of the water.
等等
Wait a second.
你不是想讓我做你的內部顧問
You're not asking me to be your in-house counsel.
你開什么玩笑
You kidding me?
大部分人都不知道算法是什么
Most people don't even know what an algorithm is.
你用它來幫助我和托尼·揚諾普洛斯
You used it to strong-arm me and Tony Gianopolous.
你有干這個的頭腦
You have a mind for this.
喬納森
Jonathan...
你不用馬上回答我
You don't have to answer right now.
考慮一下吧
Just think about this.
你現在是小打小鬧
You're in the minor leagues here.
我給了你一個大展手腳的機會
I'm giving you a chance to play in the majors.
很高興你能來
I'm glad you came.
我希望你不介意
I hope you don't mind.
我覺得你可能會喜歡
I thought you might like it.
-希拉  -只是張照片而已
- Sheila... - It's just a gesture.
是張漂亮的照片
It's a beautiful gesture.
你真是太...
You're so...
你就是一切
You're everything.
不  你不會現在要告訴我
Oh, no, is this where you tell me
你不準備搬去波士頓了吧
that you're not gonna move to Boston?
不是每個人都像你一樣看待我
Not everybody sees me the way you do.
大部分人要用好久才能了解我
Most people take a very, very long time to figure me out.
我花了很多年才讓這里的人
It's taken me years and years to get the people here to see
看透我的暴脾氣和我的...
past my short temper and my...
古怪的強迫癥
weird obsessions.
你對毒舌的愛并不奇怪
Your love of mudding is not weird.
我知道
Well, you see, I know that.
你知道還有誰知道嗎
You know who else knows that?
唐娜
Donna,
杰西卡  邁克  瑞秋和哈維
Jessica, Mike, Rachel, and Harvey.
他們欣賞我
They appreciate me.
他們是我的家人
They're my family.
我是在求你
I'm asking you...
請不要讓我離開我的家人
please don't make me leave my family.
我會搬到紐約來
I'll move to New York.
你不會后悔的
You won't regret this.
我知道我不會
I know I won't.
我發誓我會給你最好的生活
I promise I'm gonna give you the best life.
我們會成為紐約超強組合
We're gonna be a New York power couple.
白天談法律  晚上談戀愛
Law by day, love by night.
等我們有孩子了  全世界就等著看吧
And when we have kids, world, watch out.
強強組合  他們肯定很厲害
Sazs-Litts, they're gonna be ridiculous.
等等  什么
Wait, what?
說實話  我們的孩子
I mean, let's face it. Our kids?
就像是中了基因的六合彩
They hit the genetic lottery.
路易  我不想要孩子
Louis, I don't want kids.
什么
What?
他們不喜歡我
They don't get me.
什么  你在說什么啊
What? I mean, what-- what are you talking about?
我不喜歡小孩
I don't like kids.
我喜歡他們22歲然后去上法學院
I like when they're 22 and going to law school,
但我就是...
But I just...
那些是成年人
Those would be adults.
沒錯
Exactly.
不不不
No, no, no.
你現在這么想  但真正發生時
You may think that now, but when it actually happens,
當你有孩子時  那會...
when--when they're yours, it's so--
路易  我永遠不會那么想的  永遠
Louis, I'm never gonna think that, ever.
-你怎么能  -我怎么了
- How can you-- - How can I what?
這就是我
It's who I am.
希拉  我會成為父親的
Sheila, I'm gonna be a father.
路易  我們太幸福了
Louis, we're so happy.
我們會幸福的
We can be happy.
就我們兩個
Just us.
我為了你愿意放棄哈佛
I was willing to give up Harvard for you.
你就不能為我放棄點什么嗎
You can't give up something for me?
人人影視
YYeTs.com
怎么了
Well?
給她打電話
Call her.
給她打電話道歉
Call her and apologize.